export const generalEnglish = [
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The management has neither ….. nor *denied* the rumour that it was going to lay off some workers.",
    options: ["pronounced", "confirmed", "rejected", "advertised"],
    answer: "confirmed",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "Instead of ….. the issue, the speaker *digressed* to unimportant matters.",
    options: ["summarizing", "describing", "revealing", "addressing"],
    answer: "addressing",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The telephone booths were all ….. and I had to wait for more than ten minutes for one to become *vacant*.",
    options: ["locked", "busy", "occupied", "ringing"],
    answer: "occupied",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "While the first battalion *halted* its march at nightfall, the second ….. to the barracks.",
    options: ["returned", "set out", "proceeded", "turned up"],
    answer: "returned",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question: "His father is an ….. driver, but he is only a *novice*.",
    options: ["enlightened", "excellent", "poor", "experienced"],
    answer: "experienced",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The arrival of the police at the scene ….. rather than *mitigated* tension.",
    options: ["provoked", "heightened", "created", "prolonged"],
    answer: "heightened",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question: "Roses are *common* in May but ….. in November.",
    options: ["dead", "strange", "rare", "extinct"],
    answer: "rare",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "A bank clerk should be able to tell easily the difference between ….. notes and *counterfeit* ones.",
    options: ["crisp", "good", "correct", "genuine"],
    answer: "genuine",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "Last night, Uncle Joe was blind *drunk*, but this morning he is as ….. as a judge.",
    options: ["alert", "saintly", "strong", "sober"],
    answer: "sober",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "What I have is only a ….. of the famous painting; the *original* is in the National Museum.",
    options: ["duplicate", "model", "fake", "drawing"],
    answer: "duplicate",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The judge decided to *condemn* the act, but the audience wanted him to ….. it.",
    options: ["approve", "accept", "encourage", "praise"],
    answer: "approve",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The workers were asked to *abandon* the project and ….. on a new one.",
    options: ["continue", "focus", "embark", "resume"],
    answer: "resume",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "His attitude to the situation was *passive*, but his brother's was ….. .",
    options: ["indifferent", "aggressive", "active", "proactive"],
    answer: "active",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The climate in the North is very *arid*, but the South is relatively ….. .",
    options: ["damp", "humid", "wet", "moist"],
    answer: "humid",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "Despite his *stubborn* nature, he occasionally shows a ….. side.",
    options: ["flexible", "rigid", "hard", "strict"],
    answer: "flexible",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The debate became *heated*, but the moderator successfully ….. the tension.",
    options: ["diffused", "increased", "escalated", "compounded"],
    answer: "diffused",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "Their arguments were *irrelevant*, but the chairperson made them ….. to the discussion.",
    options: ["important", "noteworthy", "pertinent", "related"],
    answer: "pertinent",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "She was usually very *selfish*, but her recent actions appeared ….. .",
    options: ["generous", "kind", "considerate", "thoughtful"],
    answer: "generous",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question: "The plan was *aborted*, but they later decided to ….. it.",
    options: ["cancel", "proceed", "revisit", "abandon"],
    answer: "proceed",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The instructions were *ambiguous*, but the students found a way to make them ….. .",
    options: ["confusing", "clear", "precise", "specific"],
    answer: "clear",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The judge decided to *condemn* the act, but the audience wanted him to ….. it.",
    options: ["approve", "accept", "encourage", "praise"],
    answer: "approve",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The workers were asked to *abandon* the project and ….. on a new one.",
    options: ["continue", "focus", "embark", "resume"],
    answer: "resume",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "His attitude to the situation was *passive*, but his brother's was ….. .",
    options: ["indifferent", "aggressive", "active", "proactive"],
    answer: "active",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The climate in the North is very *arid*, but the South is relatively ….. .",
    options: ["damp", "humid", "wet", "moist"],
    answer: "humid",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "Despite his *stubborn* nature, he occasionally shows a ….. side.",
    options: ["flexible", "rigid", "hard", "strict"],
    answer: "flexible",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The debate became *heated*, but the moderator successfully ….. the tension.",
    options: ["diffused", "increased", "escalated", "compounded"],
    answer: "diffused",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "Their arguments were *irrelevant*, but the chairperson made them ….. to the discussion.",
    options: ["important", "noteworthy", "pertinent", "related"],
    answer: "pertinent",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "She was usually very *selfish*, but her recent actions appeared ….. .",
    options: ["generous", "kind", "considerate", "thoughtful"],
    answer: "generous",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question: "The plan was *aborted*, but they later decided to ….. it.",
    options: ["cancel", "proceed", "revisit", "abandon"],
    answer: "proceed",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The instructions were *ambiguous*, but the students found a way to make them ….. .",
    options: ["confusing", "clear", "precise", "specific"],
    answer: "clear",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "His ideas were considered *radical*, but her approach was more ….. .",
    options: ["moderate", "extreme", "severe", "liberal"],
    answer: "moderate",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The professor’s explanation was *concise*, but his assistant's was very ….. .",
    options: ["lengthy", "brief", "short", "precise"],
    answer: "lengthy",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The lecture was usually *engaging*, but today's session was ….. .",
    options: ["boring", "exciting", "interesting", "enlightening"],
    answer: "boring",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The artist's work was *authentic*, but the imitator's work was clearly ….. .",
    options: ["fake", "original", "genuine", "authentic"],
    answer: "fake",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The principal is known for being *lenient*, but his assistant is very ….. .",
    options: ["strict", "forgiving", "merciful", "sympathetic"],
    answer: "strict",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question: "If the jury’s verdict is “not guilty,” the defendant will be….",
    options: ["acquitted", "indicted", "pardoned", "forgiven"],
    answer: "acquitted",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "When all the items on the agenda had been discussed, the meeting was …….",
    options: ["adjourned", "dismissed", "postponed", "dissolved"],
    answer: "adjourned",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "Because the new venture was ………. Many businessmen and women went into it.",
    options: ["rich", "manageable", "lucrative", "satisfying"],
    answer: "lucrative",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question: "We save a………. of lions at the game reserve.",
    options: ["pride", "family", "band", "group"],
    answer: "pride",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "Many educationists feel that……. Punishment should still be retained in schools.",
    options: ["capital", "corporal", "corporate", "physical"],
    answer: "corporal",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question: "Freedom of movement is a ….. right of every citizen.",
    options: ["fundamental", "negotiated", "privileged", "respected"],
    answer: "fundamental",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question: "The river……… towards the sea.",
    options: ["meandered", "rolled", "ran", "trickled"],
    answer: "meandered",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question: "I…… that our team will win the match tomorrow.",
    options: ["certify", "conclude", "announce", "predict"],
    answer: "predict",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "If found guilty, he will……. all the wealth he has amassed illegally.",
    options: ["forgo", "abandon", "repay", "forfeit"],
    answer: "forfeit",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "At a……. of 200 kilometers an hour, the hurricane swept away everything in its path.",
    options: ["movement", "flow", "velocity", "drive"],
    answer: "velocity",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "The minister was removed from office because he ………. his official responsibilities.",
    options: ["performed", "abdicated", "neglected", "fulfilled"],
    answer: "neglected",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "The students made ………. effort to complete the project before the deadline.",
    options: ["an insufficient", "an immense", "a futile", "a collective"],
    answer: "a collective",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question: "She made a ………. statement that left everyone confused.",
    options: ["vague", "bold", "sarcastic", "clear"],
    answer: "vague",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "The chairman advised the committee members to ………. the rules of the association.",
    options: ["adhere to", "violate", "review", "disregard"],
    answer: "adhere to",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "The players were praised for their ………. performance during the competition.",
    options: ["lackluster", "outstanding", "average", "mediocre"],
    answer: "outstanding",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "The judge warned the lawyer against making ………. remarks in court.",
    options: ["inflammatory", "complimentary", "diplomatic", "irrelevant"],
    answer: "inflammatory",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "The governor's visit was intended to ………. the morale of the workers.",
    options: ["diminish", "boost", "criticize", "ignore"],
    answer: "boost",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "The scientist proposed a ………. solution to the environmental problem.",
    options: ["controversial", "practical", "unacceptable", "impractical"],
    answer: "practical",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question: "The teacher gave a ………. explanation of the difficult topic.",
    options: ["lengthy", "concise", "confusing", "irrelevant"],
    answer: "concise",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "The company's decision to expand was based on ………. market research.",
    options: ["hasty", "comprehensive", "flawed", "insufficient"],
    answer: "comprehensive",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question: "The protesters carried ………. banners demanding justice.",
    options: ["colorful", "bold", "irrelevant", "small"],
    answer: "bold",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "The meeting was adjourned due to a lack of ………. among the members.",
    options: ["cooperation", "arguments", "time", "participation"],
    answer: "cooperation",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question: "The football team displayed great ………. during the match.",
    options: ["cowardice", "teamwork", "apathy", "disunity"],
    answer: "teamwork",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "The committee reached a ………. decision after hours of deliberation.",
    options: ["unanimous", "divided", "controversial", "hasty"],
    answer: "unanimous",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question: "The boy was punished for his ………. behavior in class.",
    options: ["courteous", "disruptive", "polite", "obedient"],
    answer: "disruptive",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question: "The farmer used a ………. technique to increase crop yield.",
    options: ["traditional", "innovative", "outdated", "inefficient"],
    answer: "innovative",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question: "The principal emphasized the need for ………. among students.",
    options: ["discipline", "rebellion", "indifference", "laziness"],
    answer: "discipline",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "The villagers were warned about the ………. effects of deforestation.",
    options: ["beneficial", "destructive", "harmless", "minor"],
    answer: "destructive",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "The manager gave the workers a ………. deadline to complete the project.",
    options: ["flexible", "strict", "lenient", "indefinite"],
    answer: "strict",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that best completes the following sentence.",
    question:
      "The patient was advised to avoid ………. activities after the surgery.",
    options: ["strenuous", "routine", "relaxing", "light"],
    answer: "strenuous",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "When I leave this country it will be for good. This means that I will",
    options: [
      "never come back",
      "leave for better conditions elsewhere",
      "become an adventurer.",
      "improvement ways.",
    ],
    answer: "never come back",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "When she confronted her husband, he hung his head and didn’t answer her questions. This means that he was",
    options: [
      "defiant",
      "ashamed and embarrassed",
      "caught unawares",
      "angry with her",
    ],
    answer: "ashamed and embarrassed",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "All our plans fell through at the last moment. This means that we",
    options: ["were exposed", "delayed", "were abandoned", "failed"],
    answer: "failed",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The police knew that the suspect was not being straight with them. This means that the suspect was",
    options: ["not telling the truth", "not friendly", "afraid", "timid"],
    answer: "not telling the truth",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "After his prison experience, Etim decided to go straight. This means that he decided to.",
    options: [
      "hold his head up and walk with defiance",
      "change his religion",
      "live an honest life",
      "stop using drugs",
    ],
    answer: "live an honest life",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The teacher spoke with his tongue in his cheek when he said that lazy Ade was the best pupil. This means that the teacher",
    options: [
      "did not mean what he said",
      "was disappointed",
      "was angry",
      "tried to encourage",
    ],
    answer: "did not mean what he said",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "They did not know what to expect and so decided to play it by ear. This means that they decided to",
    options: [
      "listen attentively to everyone",
      "act according to circumstances",
      "pretend to be deaf",
      "prepare for the worst",
    ],
    answer: "act according to circumstances",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "Ojo decided that the best course of action was to play along with them for the time being. This means that he decided to",
    options: [
      "join their team temporarily",
      "entertain them for a while",
      "pretend to agree with them",
      "be playful with them",
    ],
    answer: "pretend to agree with them",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The conference was attended by people from all walks of life. This means that conference was attended by people",
    options: [
      "of all races",
      "who travelled widely",
      "from all professions",
      "from different parts of the world",
    ],
    answer: "from all professions",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The politician promised to give an arm and a leg for the project. This means that he",
    options: [
      "will do anything possible to achieve it",
      "will use his power to achieve it",
      "will fail to deliver on his promise",
      "will ask others for help",
    ],
    answer: "will do anything possible to achieve it",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "Ngozi is such a green-eyed monster when she sees others succeed. This means that she is",
    options: [
      "happy for others",
      "envious of others' success",
      "unconcerned about others",
      "always supportive",
    ],
    answer: "envious of others' success",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The professor’s explanation was clear as crystal. This means that it was",
    options: [
      "easy to understand",
      "hard to follow",
      "deep and meaningful",
      "confusing",
    ],
    answer: "easy to understand",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "After being exposed, the conman decided to face the music. This means he decided to",
    options: [
      "escape punishment",
      "accept the consequences",
      "sing in court",
      "argue his case",
    ],
    answer: "accept the consequences",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The new policy will take effect at the eleventh hour. This means it will",
    options: [
      "happen at the last moment",
      "never happen",
      "occur early in the day",
      "be canceled",
    ],
    answer: "happen at the last moment",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question: "His speech was a bitter pill to swallow. This means that it was",
    options: [
      "pleasant to hear",
      "difficult to accept",
      "easy to understand",
      "completely irrelevant",
    ],
    answer: "difficult to accept",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "After the heated debate, everyone decided to bury the hatchet. This means they decided to",
    options: [
      "resolve their differences",
      "continue fighting",
      "forget about the topic",
      "change the subject",
    ],
    answer: "resolve their differences",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "Mary's attitude at the meeting added fuel to the fire. This means her attitude",
    options: [
      "calmed the situation",
      "made things worse",
      "resolved the issue",
      "was ignored by others",
    ],
    answer: "made things worse",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The manager advised the staff to pull their weight. This means they should",
    options: [
      "work harder",
      "reduce their efforts",
      "support each other",
      "mind their business",
    ],
    answer: "work harder",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The news about the accident came out of the blue. This means it was",
    options: ["expected", "shocking", "unexpected", "irrelevant"],
    answer: "unexpected",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "Despite her struggles, she refused to throw in the towel. This means that she refused to",
    options: ["give up", "seek help", "lose hope", "change her mind"],
    answer: "give up",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question: "The project was shelved indefinitely. This means that it was",
    options: [
      "postponed for the time being",
      "abandoned completely",
      "given a new deadline",
      "put on hold without a set date",
    ],
    answer: "put on hold without a set date",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question: "His story sounded fishy. This means it was",
    options: ["convincing", "suspicious", "entertaining", "well-rehearsed"],
    answer: "suspicious",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The worker decided to tighten his belt after his salary was reduced. This means that he decided to",
    options: [
      "increase his expenses",
      "save more money",
      "spend less money",
      "look for another job",
    ],
    answer: "spend less money",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "She hit the nail on the head during the discussion. This means she",
    options: [
      "made an accurate point",
      "argued strongly",
      "raised an irrelevant point",
      "agreed with everyone",
    ],
    answer: "made an accurate point",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The team decided to go back to the drawing board. This means they decided to",
    options: [
      "start all over again",
      "review their progress",
      "abandon the project",
      "hire new members",
    ],
    answer: "start all over again",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question: "He bit off more than he could chew. This means he",
    options: [
      "took on a challenge too big for him",
      "refused to eat",
      "asked for help",
      "overreacted to the situation",
    ],
    answer: "took on a challenge too big for him",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The students were advised to stay on their toes. This means they should",
    options: [
      "relax and enjoy themselves",
      "be alert and prepared",
      "be careful about what they say",
      "get more rest",
    ],
    answer: "be alert and prepared",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question: "Her business is flourishing. This means it is",
    options: [
      "doing well",
      "facing challenges",
      "breaking even",
      "about to fail",
    ],
    answer: "doing well",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question: "He jumped the gun and submitted the report early. This means he",
    options: [
      "acted too soon",
      "followed instructions",
      "made an error",
      "delayed unnecessarily",
    ],
    answer: "acted too soon",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "Amina is the one who *initiated* the quarrel, not Nikel!",
    options: ["started", "stopped", "settled", "fuelled"],
    answer: "started",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "She was *reprimanded* by her boss for negligence",
    options: ["sacked", "rebuked", "punished", "surcharged"],
    answer: "rebuked",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "Why should I *retract* my statement when it is nothing but the truth?",
    options: ["alter", "deny", "withdraw", "condemn"],
    answer: "withdraw",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The doctor diagnosed the tumour as *malignant*",
    options: ["deadly", "painful", "trouble", "minor"],
    answer: "deadly",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "In tropical Africa, mosquitoes are *ubiquitous*",
    options: ["dangerous", "harmful", "trouble", "everywhere"],
    answer: "everywhere",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "It soon became obvious that a confrontation was *inevitable*",
    options: ["disastrous", "unavoidable", "desirable", "imminent"],
    answer: "unavoidable",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "They insisted that the omission of my name had been *inadvertent*",
    options: ["unintentional", "unconditional", "improper", "unfortunate"],
    answer: "unintentional",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The police announced that they were yet to *apprehend* the criminals",
    options: ["interrogated", "charge", "prosecute", "arrest"],
    answer: "arrest",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "He is easily recognizable because of a *conspicuous* birthmark on his face",
    options: ["dark", "beautiful", "prominent", "natural"],
    answer: "prominent",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The *chaotic* situation in the market was beyond control.",
    options: ["organized", "disorderly", "quiet", "calm"],
    answer: "disorderly",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The *exuberant* crowd cheered the team to victory.",
    options: ["joyful", "angry", "silent", "fearful"],
    answer: "joyful",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The *ardent* supporter refused to leave the stadium.",
    options: ["casual", "enthusiastic", "indifferent", "apathetic"],
    answer: "enthusiastic",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The *imposing* structure stood out as the tallest in the city.",
    options: ["modest", "diminutive", "grand", "insignificant"],
    answer: "grand",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The decision was made after careful *deliberation*.",
    options: ["debate", "confusion", "reflection", "improvisation"],
    answer: "reflection",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "Her *ambiguous* answer left everyone confused.",
    options: ["clear", "uncertain", "direct", "precise"],
    answer: "uncertain",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "His *courageous* act inspired many people.",
    options: ["fearless", "timid", "cowardly", "careful"],
    answer: "fearless",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The teacher asked the students to *recollect* the main points of the lesson.",
    options: ["remember", "forget", "summarize", "discuss"],
    answer: "remember",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "Her *benevolent* nature made her the favorite among the children.",
    options: ["kind", "harsh", "selfish", "lazy"],
    answer: "kind",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The child showed *aptitude* for learning mathematics.",
    options: ["interest", "failure", "ability", "dislike"],
    answer: "ability",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The *vivid* description of the event made it come alive in my mind.",
    options: ["vague", "dull", "clear", "obscure"],
    answer: "clear",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The *mundane* tasks of daily life bored him.",
    options: ["exciting", "dull", "important", "complicated"],
    answer: "dull",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The novel’s *enigmatic* ending left many readers puzzled.",
    options: ["confusing", "clear", "boring", "predictable"],
    answer: "confusing",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "She felt *exhilarated* after completing the marathon.",
    options: ["tired", "disappointed", "excited", "fearful"],
    answer: "excited",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "His *benevolence* towards the less fortunate was remarkable.",
    options: ["selfishness", "kindness", "greed", "anger"],
    answer: "kindness",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The teacher *disciplined* the student for his misbehavior.",
    options: ["punished", "praised", "ignored", "rewarded"],
    answer: "punished",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The artist's *innovative* style set him apart from others.",
    options: ["traditional", "creative", "lazy", "ordinary"],
    answer: "creative",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The children were *elated* when they saw the surprise party.",
    options: ["happy", "sad", "angry", "bored"],
    answer: "happy",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The politician’s *controversial* statement sparked a nationwide debate.",
    options: ["disputed", "accepted", "praise-worthy", "ignored"],
    answer: "disputed",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "She gave a *cogent* argument for why she should receive the promotion.",
    options: ["weak", "compelling", "confusing", "insufficient"],
    answer: "compelling",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "His *mild* reaction to the news surprised everyone.",
    options: ["strong", "gentle", "extreme", "angry"],
    answer: "gentle",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "Her *unwavering* faith in her team led them to victory.",
    options: ["unsteady", "firm", "weak", "uncertain"],
    answer: "firm",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The children were *ecstatic* when they saw the surprise gift.",
    options: ["sad", "angry", "joyful", "confused"],
    answer: "joyful",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "His *charitable* nature earned him the respect of many.",
    options: ["selfish", "generous", "lazy", "shy"],
    answer: "generous",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "She gave a *succinct* response that satisfied all questions.",
    options: ["long", "detailed", "brief", "unclear"],
    answer: "brief",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The director’s *meticulous* approach to the project ensured its success.",
    options: ["careless", "thorough", "quick", "incomplete"],
    answer: "thorough",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The *insightful* comments helped improve the quality of the presentation.",
    options: ["ignorant", "valuable", "unclear", "misleading"],
    answer: "valuable",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The *enigmatic* statement left everyone in confusion.",
    options: ["simple", "obvious", "mysterious", "predictable"],
    answer: "mysterious",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The student’s *conscientious* work earned him the best grade.",
    options: ["careless", "diligent", "lazy", "indifferent"],
    answer: "diligent",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "Her *exemplary* behavior set a good example for her peers.",
    options: ["bad", "poor", "outstanding", "irrelevant"],
    answer: "outstanding",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "His *impulsive* decision to buy the car was regretted later.",
    options: ["calculated", "spontaneous", "thoughtful", "planned"],
    answer: "spontaneous",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "Her *aloof* attitude made it difficult for others to approach her.",
    options: ["friendly", "distant", "attentive", "engaged"],
    answer: "distant",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The *abrasive* remarks of the manager upset the employees.",
    options: ["polite", "harsh", "gentle", "thoughtful"],
    answer: "harsh",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The *precarious* situation required immediate attention.",
    options: ["stable", "dangerous", "safe", "peaceful"],
    answer: "dangerous",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The *transitory* nature of life teaches us to appreciate every moment.",
    options: ["permanent", "brief", "eternal", "slow"],
    answer: "brief",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The team’s *cohesive* effort led to their success.",
    options: ["divided", "united", "confused", "lazy"],
    answer: "united",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "His *insatiable* appetite for knowledge made him an excellent student.",
    options: ["limited", "unquenchable", "satisfied", "bored"],
    answer: "unquenchable",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The child’s *melancholy* expression showed his disappointment.",
    options: ["cheerful", "sad", "excited", "happy"],
    answer: "sad",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The book was *intriguing* and kept me hooked from start to finish.",
    options: ["boring", "captivating", "predictable", "uninteresting"],
    answer: "captivating",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "His *lucid* explanation helped everyone understand the topic.",
    options: ["clear", "vague", "complicated", "confusing"],
    answer: "clear",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From the options below, choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the asterisked word as it is used in the sentence.",
    question: "The *scanty* evidence made it difficult to prove the case.",
    options: ["ample", "insufficient", "clear", "obvious"],
    answer: "insufficient",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The workers were *overjoyed* when they received their bonuses, but the management was ……",
    options: ["indifferent", "pleased", "disheartened", "thrilled"],
    answer: "disheartened",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "His decision to leave the company was *premature*, and it left his colleagues feeling ……",
    options: ["eager", "untroubled", "disappointed", "satisfied"],
    answer: "disappointed",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The teacher's explanation was *clear* and concise, but the students were still ……",
    options: ["confused", "enlightened", "relieved", "assured"],
    answer: "confused",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The new project was a *success* in every aspect, and the team felt ……",
    options: ["defeated", "accomplished", "successful", "proud"],
    answer: "defeated",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "Despite the *harsh* criticism, the manager remained calm and composed, while his assistant was ……",
    options: ["nervous", "relaxed", "carefree", "happy"],
    answer: "nervous",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "His *generosity* towards his colleagues was well-known, and he expected nothing in return, unlike the *selfish* attitude of others.",
    options: ["unkind", "considerate", "warm-hearted", "kind"],
    answer: "unkind",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question: "The weather was *unpredictable* yesterday, but today it is ……",
    options: ["stable", "uncertain", "changeable", "sporadic"],
    answer: "stable",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The school's *strict* policies were sometimes *lenient*, making it difficult to maintain discipline.",
    options: ["relaxed", "lenient", "firm", "demanding"],
    answer: "relaxed",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The *foolish* behavior of the students was ignored by the teacher, while the *wise* ones received praise.",
    options: ["wise", "careless", "logical", "thoughtful"],
    answer: "wise",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "Despite the *harsh* treatment, she remained calm and composed, while the others were ……",
    options: ["angry", "calm", "defensive", "shaken"],
    answer: "angry",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "He made a *temporary* arrangement to resolve the situation, but things became ……",
    options: ["permanent", "long-lasting", "brief", "momentary"],
    answer: "permanent",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question: "The *aggressive* approach to solving the problem resulted in ……",
    options: ["peaceful", "assertive", "calm", "passive"],
    answer: "peaceful",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "His *consistent* hard work paid off, but his colleague's *inconsistent* performance left them……",
    options: ["relaxed", "confident", "shaky", "steady"],
    answer: "shaky",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The student's *outstanding* performance in the exam was praised by everyone, while the others felt ……",
    options: ["average", "remarkable", "exceptional", "superb"],
    answer: "average",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The new manager was *reluctant* to implement changes, while the team felt ……",
    options: ["enthusiastic", "indifferent", "refusing", "willing"],
    answer: "enthusiastic",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The politician's *inflammatory* speech sparked tensions, while the public's response was ……",
    options: ["peaceful", "unremarkable", "angry", "emotional"],
    answer: "peaceful",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The *shrewd* businessman made excellent investments, while his less *astute* competitors faced ……",
    options: ["successful", "prudent", "lackluster", "intelligent"],
    answer: "lackluster",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "The manager gave a *vague* response, which left the employees feeling ……",
    options: ["clear", "certain", "indifferent", "unsure"],
    answer: "clear",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "Choose the one that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the asterisked word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
    question:
      "Despite his *exuberant* personality, he was often met with a ……. attitude from his colleagues.",
    options: ["cheerful", "reserved", "warm", "friendly"],
    answer: "reserved",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "He was walking on *air* after receiving the good news. This means he was",
    options: ["nervous", "sad", "elated", "confused"],
    answer: "elated",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "She *bent over backwards* to help her friend, even though she was tired. This means she",
    options: [
      "worked hard",
      "ignored her needs",
      "helped excessively",
      "did not care",
    ],
    answer: "helped excessively",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The candidate *pulled no punches* during the interview. This means the candidate",
    options: [
      "was very honest",
      "was very cautious",
      "lied about his experience",
      "was nervous",
    ],
    answer: "was very honest",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The director’s decision to hire the new actor was a *masterstroke*. This means it was a",
    options: [
      "terrible mistake",
      "wise and effective move",
      "weak decision",
      "risky decision",
    ],
    answer: "wise and effective move",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The event was a *mixed bag* of good and bad experiences. This means the event was",
    options: [
      "completely bad",
      "predictable",
      "unorganized",
      "a combination of positive and negative",
    ],
    answer: "a combination of positive and negative",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question: "He was *caught red-handed* by the police. This means he was",
    options: [
      "misunderstood",
      "caught while committing a crime",
      "innocent",
      "accused without proof",
    ],
    answer: "caught while committing a crime",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "She’s *in the same boat* as you regarding the assignment. This means she is",
    options: [
      "better off than you",
      "facing the same problem",
      "not involved in the situation",
      "disinterested",
    ],
    answer: "facing the same problem",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "His explanation was *as clear as mud*. This means his explanation was",
    options: ["extremely detailed", "confusing", "perfectly clear", "precise"],
    answer: "confusing",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The new proposal was *a breath of fresh air* compared to the old ones. This means the proposal was",
    options: [
      "boring",
      "completely new and refreshing",
      "unclear",
      "difficult to understand",
    ],
    answer: "completely new and refreshing",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The charity event was *a drop in the ocean* compared to the funds needed. This means the event was",
    options: ["very helpful", "insufficient", "immense", "well-planned"],
    answer: "insufficient",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The teacher gave him *the benefit of the doubt* when he explained why he was late. This means the teacher",
    options: [
      "believed the excuse",
      "doubted his excuse",
      "gave him a second chance",
      "punished him",
    ],
    answer: "believed the excuse",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "Her decision to quit was *out of the frying pan and into the fire*. This means her decision was",
    options: [
      "a step up",
      "a better opportunity",
      "a poor decision",
      "a lucky break",
    ],
    answer: "a poor decision",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "He *put all his eggs in one basket* when he invested all his money in one business. This means he",
    options: [
      "diversified his investments",
      "took a risk by relying on one option",
      "invested wisely",
      "was cautious",
    ],
    answer: "took a risk by relying on one option",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The politician’s promises were *just smoke and mirrors*. This means the promises were",
    options: [
      "honest and clear",
      "meaningless and deceptive",
      "reasonable",
      "guaranteed to succeed",
    ],
    answer: "meaningless and deceptive",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "They finally decided to *call it a day* after hours of work. This means they decided to",
    options: [
      "take a break",
      "finish for the day",
      "continue working",
      "take a nap",
    ],
    answer: "finish for the day",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "His attempt to explain the issue was *a wild goose chase*. This means his attempt was",
    options: ["successful", "futile", "clear", "effective"],
    answer: "futile",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "After months of training, she was *raring to go* on the day of the competition. This means she was",
    options: ["uninterested", "reluctant", "excited", "nervous"],
    answer: "excited",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The team's performance in the final game was *the last straw* for the coach. This means it was",
    options: [
      "a minor issue",
      "the final disappointment",
      "an unexpected success",
      "a major achievement",
    ],
    answer: "the final disappointment",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "He managed to *get his act together* after the setback. This means he managed to",
    options: [
      "become disorganized",
      "fail again",
      "become more focused",
      "lose hope",
    ],
    answer: "become more focused",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "She *let the cat out of the bag* about the surprise party. This means she",
    options: [
      "kept the secret",
      "discovered the surprise",
      "revealed the secret unintentionally",
      "ignored the surprise",
    ],
    answer: "revealed the secret unintentionally",
  },
  {
    instruction:
      "From options A to D, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for this sentence.",
    question:
      "The new manager’s style was *a breath of fresh air* compared to the old one. This means the new manager was",
    options: [
      "dull and uninspiring",
      "refreshing and new",
      "unfriendly",
      "strict",
    ],
    answer: "refreshing and new",
  },
];
